E. Adamson Hoebel Papers 1925-1983 Mss.Ms.Coll.43
American Philosophical Society
- Series I. Correspondence, 1931-1992; 9 boxes; 4.75 linear feet
  - Ghiselin, Brewster, 1960 (Box 3)
  - Gibbs, James Lowell, Jr., 1955, 1969-1985 (Box 3)
  - Gifford, Edward, 1941 (Box 3)
  - Gilles, Albert S., Sr., 1977 (Box 3)
  - Gillin, John P., 1941-1972 (Box 3)
  - Gladwin, Thomas, 1961 (Box 3)
  - Glaser, Ezra, 1941 (Box 3)
  - Gluckman, Mary, 1974-1979 (Box 3)
  - Gluckman, Max, 1948-1977, n.d. (Box 3)
  - Gold, Gerald Louis, 1970 (Box 3)
  - Goldfrank, Esther S. (Box 3)
  - Goldman, Ira, 1970 (Box 3)
  - Goldsby, Richard A., 1971 (Box 3)
  - Goldschmidt, Walter, 1952-1956 (Box 3)
    Casagrande, Joseph
  - Grand Canyon Corporation, 1968-1972 (Box 3)
    See also Ser.II, Grand Canyon Expedition
  - Graziano, William G., 1977 (Box 3)
  - Graubard, Mark, 1983 (Box 3)
  - Greenamyre, Edward L., 1986 (Box 3)
  - Griffith, Gwendolyn, 1952 (Box 3)
  - The Grolier Society, Inc., 1946 (Box 3)
  - The Harry Frank Guggenheim Foundation, 1982 (Box 3)
  - Gulliver, Philip, 1969-1970 (Box 3)
  - Haar, Charles M., 1968 (Box 3)
  - Hall, Jerome, 1962 (Box 3)
    Schiller, A. Arthur
  - Hallowell, A. Irving, 1960 (Box 3)
  - Hamdani, L. Hasan Jahangir, 1962 (Box 3)
  - Hamline University, 1978, 1984, n.d. (Box 3)
  - Hampshire College, 1969 (Box 3)
  - Hamson, Daniel M., 1972 (Box 3)
  - Handbook of North American Indians, 1971-1983, n.d. (Box 4)
  - Hanson, Richard, 1941 (Box 4)
  - Harcourt, Brace and World, 1969 (Box 4)
  - Harper and Brothers Publishing, 1938 (Box 4)
  - Harvard University, 1941, 1952, 1961 (Box 4)
  - Harvard University Press, 1953-1954, 1975 (Box 4)
  - Haskell Indian College, 1991 (Box 4)
  - Hatcher, Evelyn Payne, 1969-1988, n.d. (Box 4)
    McGraw-Hill
  - Hatcher, Jack, 1970 (Box 4)
  - Haury, Emil W., 1985, 1988 (Box 4)
  - Hawkins, Carl S., 1970 (Box 4)
  - Hawkins, Gerald S., 1968 (Box 4)
  - Headrick, Cecil W., 1941, 1955-1957, n.d. (Box 4)
  - Headrick, Daniel, 1982 (Box 4)
  - Heckel, Robert L., 1961-1962 (Box 4)
  - Hehmyer, Alexander, 1970 (Box 4)
  - Herring, Pendleton, 1960 (Box 4)
    See also Ser.I, The Social Science Research Council
  - Hester, E.D., 1944 (Box 4)
  - Hidy, Ralph W., 1956 (Box 4)
  - Hiebert, Paul G., 1969-1984 (Box 4)
  - Hockett, Charles F., 1972-1982 (Box 4)
  - Hoebel, Irene, 1975, 1981, 1985 (Box 4)
  - Holleman, J.F., 1970-1973, 1985 (Box 4)
  - Holsopple, J.Q., 1941 (Box 4)
  - Holt, Rinehart and Winston, 1965, 1979 (Box 4)
  - Honeywell, Inc., 1970 (Box 4)
  - Hossain, Kamal, 1955 (Box 4)
  - Hostetler, John A., 1964 (Box 4)
  - Houge, Benjamin S., 1971 (Box 4)
  - Houghton Mifflin Company, 1942 (Box 4)
  - Howell, F. Clark, 1967 (Box 4)
  - Howells, W.W., 1970 (Box 4)
  - Hsu, Francis L.K., 1954-1984 (Box 4)
    Currier, Richard L.; Kaiser, Susan; Merriam, Alan; See also Ser.I, Currier, Richard L.
  - Huber, O.A., 1955 (Box 4)
    Wallace, Ernest
  - Hughes, Everett C., 1968 (Box 4)
  - Human Relations Area Files, Inc., 1990 (Box 4)
  - Humphrey, Hubert H., 1967, 1971 (Box 4)
    See also Ser.I, McLaughlin, Mr. and Mrs. Ronald C.; See also Ser.I, Visscher, Maurice B.
  - Illinois State University, 1979-1980 (Box 4)
    Reyman, Jonathan E.
  - Ing, Dean C., 1968 (Box 4)
  - Institute for World Understanding, 1985 (Box 4)
  - Inter-Allied Publications, 1945 (Box 4)
  - International Cooperation Administration, 1960 (Box 4)
  - International Encyclopedia of the Social Sciences, 1964-1966 (Box 4)
  - Islam, A.K.M. Aminul, 1967-1971 (Box 4)
  - Iverson, Noel, 1973 (Box 4)
  - Jacobs, Melville, 1938-1946, n.d. (Box 4)
  - Jacobs, Sue-Ellen, 1979-1980, n.d. (Box 4)
  - Jennings, Jesse D., 1963 (Box 4)
  - Jerome Foundation, Inc., 1979 (Box 4)
  - Johnson, Cheryll A., 1972 (Box 4)
  - Johnson, Nourse, 1943 (Box 4)
  - Johnson, O. Elden, 1969, 1980-1985 (Box 4)
  - Johnson, Rich, 1986 (Box 4)
  - Jonassen, Christen T., 1968-1969, 1982 (Box 4)
  - Jones, Harry, 1945 (Box 4)
  - Journal of American Folk-Lore, 1938-1941 (Box 4)
  - Journal of Criminal Law and Criminology, 1941 (Box 4)
  - The Journal of Developing Areas, 1975 (Box 4)
  - Journal of the Royal Anthropological Institute (Box 4)
  - Kaiser, Susan, 1979 (Box 4)
    See also Ser.I, Beals, Ralph L.; See also Ser.I, Eggan, Fred; See also Ser.I, Hsu, Francis L.K.; See also Ser.I, Kirsch, Anthony T.; See also Ser.I, Lancaster, Jane B.; See also Ser.I, Scholte, Bob
  - Kando, Thomas F., 1962-1973 (Box 4)
  - Kane, Stanley D., 1971-1972 (Box 4)
  - Katholieke Universiteit, 1967-1981 (Box 4)
  - Kavanagh, Thomas W., 1990 (Box 4)
  - Keithahn, Edward L., 1939-1942 (Box 4)
  - Kemper, Robert V., 1979 (Box 4)
  - Kennedy, Raymond, 1945 (Box 4)
  - Keshavjee, Rafique H., 1971-1972 (Box 4)
  - Khajanchi, M.G., 1961-1962 (Box 4)
  - Kimura, Craig C., 1971 (Box 4)
  - Kimura, Emi, 1945 (Box 4)
  - Kirsch, Anthony Thomas, 1975-1980 (Box 4)
  - Kiste, Robert Carl, 1970-1987, n.d. (Box 4)
  - Kluckhohn, Clyde, 1941 (Box 4)
  - Knudson, Ruthann, 1983 (Box 4)
  - Konner, Melvin Joel, 1979-1982, n.d. (Box 4)
  - Kozolchyk, Boris, 1987 (Box 4)
  - Krinkin, Alexandra, [194-] (Box 5)
  - Kroeber, Alfred L., 1940-1945 (Box 5)
  - Krout, John A., 1940 (Box 5)
  - La Barre, Weston, 1936-1982 (Box 5)
  - Laboratory of Anthropology, 1933-1940 (Box 5)
    Mekeel, H. Scudder
  - Lal, Kanwar Prem, 1978 (Box 5)
    Burke, S.M.
  - Lancaster, Jane Beckman, 1979-1980, n.d. (Box 5)
  - Landes, Ruth, 1940 (Box 5)
  - Landheer, B, 1953, 1985 (Box 5)
    See also Ser.II, World Law Project
  - Lane, Richard B., 1969 (Box 5)
  - Lane, Robert B., 1973 (Box 5)
  - Lang, Gottfried O., 1954-1983 (Box 5)
  - Lange, Charles H., 1959, 1968, 1973 (Box 5)
  - Lantis, Margaret, 1945 (Box 5)
  - Law and Behavioral Research Symposium, 1980-1981 (Box 5)
  - Law and Society Association, 1989 (Box 5)
  - Law and Society Review, 1968-1972 (Box 5)
  - Leh, L.L., 1938 (Box 5)
  - Lehigh University, 1980 (Box 5)
  - Lehmann, F.R., 1950 (Box 5)
  - Leonard, Joan, 1981 (Box 5)
  - Leslie, Charles, 1957-1968 (Box 5)
  - Lewin, Julius, 1948 (Box 5)
  - Lewis, Sandra, 1971 (Box 5)
  - Leydet, Francois G., 1986 (Box 5)
  - Lin, Vincent T.G., 1965-1966, 1971 (Box 5)
  - Lindig, Wolfgang, 1964 (Box 5)
  - Linton, Ralph, 1933-1948 (Box 5)
    See also Ser.I, American Anthropologist
  - Lippo, Susie (Box 5)
    See Ser.I, Lippo, William
  - Lippo, William, 1945 (Box 5)
    Lippo, Susie
  - Lips, Julius E., 1935, 1938-1939 (Box 5)
  - Livermore, Joseph M., 1975, 1987 (Box 5)
  - Llewellyn, Emma, 1971, n.d. (Box 5)
  - Llewellyn, Karl N., 1934-1946, 1987, n.d. (Box 5)
    See also Ser.I, Krout, John A.; See also Ser.I, Social Science Research Council. Institute in Law and Social Relations
  - Lock, Michele R., 1978 (Box 5)
  - Lockhart, William B., 1968 (Box 5)
  - Loeb, Edwin M., 1941 (Box 5)
  - Long, Joseph K., 1967 (Box 5)
  - Ray Long and Richard R. Smith, Inc., 1933 (Box 5)
  - Lord, Anthony, 1972 (Box 5)
  - Lovell, Tom, 1970 (Box 5)
  - Lowie, Robert H., 1933-1947 (Box 5)
  - Luomala, Katharine, 1979 (Box 5)
  - Lynch, Owen W., 1979-1983 (Box 5)
  - McAllester, David P., 1968 (Box 5)
  - McCabe, Gerry, 1971 (Box 5)
  - McCown, Theodore D., 1947 (Box 5)
  - McGraw-Hill (Box 5)
    See also Ser.I, Hatcher, Evelyn
  - ***Folder #1, 1934-1969 (Box 5)
  - ***Folder #2, 1970-1991, n.d. (Box 5)
  - McGregor, Gordon, 1945 (Box 5)
  - MacIver, R.M., 1933 (Box 5)
  - McLaughlin, Ronald (Mr. & Mrs.), 1956 (Box 5)
    Humphrey, Hubert H.; See also Ser.II, World Law Project
  - McMillan, Robert L., 1973 (Box 5)
    See also Ser.I., Mead, Margaret
  - The Macmillman Company, 1948 (Box 5)
  - McNickle, D'Arcy, 1973 (Box 5)
  - Mandelbaum, David, 1957-1981, n.d. (Box 5)
  - Martin, Elizabeth, 1959 (Box 5)
  - Mead, Margaret, 1972-1973 (Box 5)
    McMillman, Robert L.; See also Ser.I, American Anthropological Association
  - Medina, Juanito, 1946, 1982 (Box 5)
  - Medina, Lena, 1983 (Box 5)
  - Medina, S.J., 1946 (Box 5)
  - Mekeel, H. Scudder (Box 5)
    See Ser.I, Laboratory of Anthropology; See Ser.I, United States Department of the Interior
  - Memoirs of the American Anthropological Association, 1940 (Box 5)
  - Merriam, Alan (Box 5)
    See Ser.I, Hsu, Francis L.K.
  - Merrill, William L., 1983 (Box 5)
  - Middlebury College, 1935 (Box 5)
  - Miller, Jay, 1975, 1981-1982 (Box 5)
  - Miller, Richard E., 1981 (Box 5)
  - Minneapolis Public Library and Information Center, 1986 (Box 5)
  - Minnesota. Department of Health, 1973 (Box 5)
  - Modell, Judy, 1972 (Box 6)
    Bieder, Robert E.; See also Ser.I, Wallis, Ruth
  - Mondale, Walter F., 1973, 1983 (Box 6)
  - Montagu, Ashley, 1967 (Box 6)
  - Moore, Harvey C., 1959 (Box 6)
  - Moore, John H., 1972 (Box 6)
  - Moore, Sally, 1974 (Box 6)
  - Moos, Malcolm, 1968 (Box 6)
  - Mordy, Wendell Allen, 1977, n.d. (Box 6)
    See also Ser.I, The Science Museum of Minnesota
  - Moreau, Frederick, 1973, n.d. (Box 6)
  - Morrill, J. L., 1955 (Box 6)
  - Morin, Alexander J., 1979 (Box 6)
  - Morrison, Charles, 1982 (Box 6)
  - Mosely, Philip E. (Box 6)
    See Ser.I, United States Arms Control and Disarmament Agency
  - Movius, Hallam L., Jr., 1953 (Box 6)
  - Murdock, George P., 1939, 1942, 1947 (Box 6)
    See also Ser.I, American Anthropological Association; See also Ser.I, The Society for Applied Anthropology
  - Muti-Ul-Haq, Shafiqua, 1970 (Box 6)
  - Nader, Laura, 1964-1971 (Box 6)
  - Narain, S., 1968 (Box 6)
  - National Association on Standard Medical Vocabulary, 1962 (Box 6)
  - National Commission on Law Observance and Enforcement, 1931 (Box 6)
  - National Endowment for the Humanities, 1983, n.d. (Box 6)
  - National Science Foundation, 1967-1982, n.d. (Box 6)
  - Natural Law Forum, 1963-1969 (Box 6)
  - Needham, Claudia, 1968 (Box 6)
  - Needham, Rodney, 1959, 1978 (Box 6)
  - Nelson, Lowry, 1954 (Box 6)
  - Nemzoff, Sol, 1945 (Box 6)
  - Neubert, Ruth, 1945 (Box 6)
  - The New York School for Social Research, 1940 (Box 6)
  - New York State Bar Journal, 1970 (Box 6)
  - New York University, 1929-1955 (Box 6)
    Dittmer, C.G.
  - Ney, Edward P., 1971 (Box 6)
  - Nicholson, 1970 (Box 6)
  - Nicholson, Maggi E. Read, 1971-1989, n.d. (Box 6)
  - Norbeck, Edward, 1960 (Box 6)
  - Northrop, Filmer S.C., 1963 (Box 6)
  - Nowles, Marguerite K., 1970 (Box 6)
  - Oceana Publications, 1962 (Box 6)
  - Odenyo, Amos, 1970-1971 (Box 6)
  - Ogren, Quentin, 1970 (Box 6)
  - Okie, Richardson B., 1968 (Box 6)
  - O'Leary, E. John, 1982 (Box 6)
  - Olila, James H., 1984-1985 (Box 6)
  - Oliver, Douglas, 1952-1988, n.d. (Box 6)
    Oliver, Margaret
  - Oliver, Margaret (Box 6)
    See Ser.I, Oliver, Douglas
  - Oneale, Lila M., 1945 (Box 6)
  - Opler, Marvin K., 1937, 1941 (Box 6)
  - Opler, Morris E., 1940-1941, 1975, n.d. (Box 6)
  - The Pacific Northwest Quarterly, 1940-1941 (Box 6)
  - Paddock, John, 1971-1978, n.d. (Box 6)
  - Paredes, J. Anthony, 1978 (Box 6)
  - Park, Willard Z., 1935, 1940 (Box 6)
  - Parker, Scott, 1971 (Box 6)
  - The Pepperdine School of Law, 1970 (Box 6)
  - Perlman, Isadore, 1971 (Box 6)
  - Petersen, Karen Daniels, 1961, 1964, 1967 (Box 6)
  - Piedmont Publishing Company, 1970 (Box 6)
  - Pilling, Arnold R., 1966-1968 (Box 6)
  - Plains Anthropologist, 1979-1984 (Box 6)
  - Plains Conference, 1987 (Box 6)
  - Porter, Philip W., 1981-1983 (Box 6)
  - Pospisil, Leopold, 1959-1973 (Box 6)
  - Potter, Nigel J., 1970 (Box 6)
  - Powell, Peter J., 1960-1984 (Box 6)
  - Praus, Alexis A., 1938-1984 (Box 6)
  - Price, H. Marcus III, 1988-1989 (Box 6)
  - Provine, John H., 1938 (Box 6)
  - Pryor, Frederic L., 1974 (Box 6)
  - Quimby, George, 1947 (Box 6)
  - Radford, Peter, 1968 (Box 6)
  - Radin, Max, 1941 (Box 6)
  - Radin, Paul, 1942 (Box 6)
  - Rajput, Mohammad, 1971-1983 (Box 6)
  - Raup, Phillip M., 1971 (Box 6)
  - Ray, Verne F. (Box 6)
  - The Reader's Digest, 1949 (Box 7)
  - Ream, Davidson, 1965 (Box 7)
  - Redfield, Robert, 1954 (Box 7)
    See also Ser.I, The University of Chicago; See also Ser.II, World Law Project
  - The Religion in Education Foundation, 1968-1969 (Box 7)
  - Reyman, Jonathan E., 1975-1980 (Box 7)
    See also Ser.I, Illinois State University
  - Rijksuniversiteit Te Leiden, 1970 (Box 7)
    See also Ser. III, "National Law, Legal Pluralism, and Civil Liberties"
  - Robbins, Mike, 1972 (Box 7)
  - Roberts, John M., 1959, 1964, 1968 (Box 7)
  - Robison, Barbara, 1974 (Box 7)
  - Robison, Roy C., 1974 (Box 7)
  - Rohrl, Vivian J., 1973-1989 (Box 7)
  - The Rockefeller Foundation, 1963 (Box 7)
  - The Ronald Press Company, 1944 (Box 7)
  - Rose, Arnold, 1954 (Box 7)
  - Rose, Daniel M., 1968 (Box 7)
  - Rosenbaum, D.L., 1964 (Box 7)
  - Ross, E.A., 1928-1940 (Box 7)
    See also Ser.I, The University of Wisconsin
  - Roth, Maren, 1972 (Box 7)
  - Rowland, Willis, 1939, 1941 (Box 7)
  - Ruger, Mary, 1945 (Box 7)
  - Russell, J. Townsend, 1933-1934 (Box 7)
  - Rutgers Law Review, 1962-1964 (Box 7)
  - Sacks, Ruth, 1966 (Box 7)
  - Saetveit, Philip, 1972 (Box 7)
  - San Diego. Police Department, 1970 (Box 7)
  - Sanford, Nevitt, 1980, n.d. (Box 7)
  - Saint Bridget School, 1973 (Box 7)
  - Saint Paul Institute, 1954 (Box 7)
  - Sánchez Pérez, Ana Q., 1963 (Box 7)
    some in Spanish
  - Sane, 1968 (Box 7)
  - Sapir, Edward (Box 7)
    See Ser.I, American Anthropological Association
  - Scheier, Edwin, 1979 (Box 7)
  - Schiller, A. Arthur (Box 7)
    See Ser.I, Hall, Jerome; See Ser.I, Social Science Research Council. Institute in Law and Social Relations
  - Scholte, Bob, 1975-1982 (Box 7)
    Currier, Richard L; Kaiser, Susan
  - Schorin, Howard, 1970 (Box 7)
  - Schroeder, Eileen M., 1978 (Box 7)
  - Schwartz, Alta, 1941 (Box 7)
  - Schwartz, Richard D., 1966 (Box 7)
  - The Science Museum of Minnesota, 1966-1986, n.d. (Box 7)
  - The Scientific Monthly, 1947 (Box 7)
  - Scullin, Michael, 1972 (Box 7)
  - Scully, Bede, 1940-1941 (Box 7)
  - Seagle, William, 1941, 1947, n.d. (Box 7)
  - Sengstock, Mary C., 1975 (Box 7)
  - Service, Elman R., 1973, 1979 (Box 7)
  - Shand, R.T., 1967-1968 (Box 7)
  - Shapiro, Harry L., 1945-1980, n.d. (Box 7)
  - Shaw, Geoffrey, 1975 (Box 7)
  - Shepardson, Mary, 1972 (Box 7)
  - Shepherd, William G., 1967 (Box 7)
  - Shimkin, Demitri, 1939 (Box 7)
  - Sibley, Elbridge, 1972-1987 (Box 7)
    See also Ser.I, Social Science Research Council; See also Ser.I, Social Science Research Council. Institute in Law and Social Relations
  - Silverburg, Sanford R., 1978 (Box 7)
  - Sinha, Dharni P., 1967-1990 (Box 7)
  - Skafte, Peter, 1978 (Box 7)
  - Slaats, H, 1974 (Box 7)
  - Smith, Daniel, 1962 (Box 7)
  - Smith, Marian W., 1946, 1949 (Box 7)
  - Smith, Newton and Alice, 1978 (Box 7)
  - Smith, Robert J., 1982 (Box 7)
  - Smith, Watson, 1955-1956 (Box 7)
  - Smithson, Carma Lee, 1955, n.d. (Box 7)
  - The Smithsonian Institution, 1935-1991 (Box 7)
  - Snyder, Charles, 1963 (Box 7)
  - Social Meaning of Legal Concepts, 1947-1948 (Box 7)
  - Social Science Research Council, 1941-1970 (Box 7)
    Sibley, Elbridge; See also Ser.II, same title
  - Social Science Research Council. Institute in Law and Social Relations, 2 folders (Box 7)
    Berman, Harold J.; Llewellyn, Karl N.; Schiller, A. Arthur; Sibley, Elbridge; See also Ser.II, same title
    - Folder 1, 1955-Feb. 1956 (Box 7)
    - Folder 2, Mar. 1956-1957 (Box 7)
  - The Society for Applied Anthropology, 1948 (Box 7)
    Murdock, George P.
  - Society of Professional Anthropologists, 1979 (Box 7)
  - Southeast Asia Institute, 1946-1947 (Box 7)
  - Spain, David, 1979-1982 (Box 7)
  - Spier, Leslie (Box 7)
    See Ser.I, American Anthropologist
  - Spindler, George D., 1958-1977 (Box 7)
  - Spindler, Louise (Box 7)
    See also Ser.I, Spindler, George D.
  - Spring Hill Conference, 1979-1982 (Box 8)
  - Sroll, Leo, 1940 (Box 8)
  - Stanford Law Review, 1962 (Box 8)
  - Stern, Arthur, 1979 (Box 8)
  - Stevens, Henry S., 1941 (Box 8)
  - Stevenson, Adlai E., 1964 (Box 8)
  - Steward, Julian H., 1936-1940 (Box 8)
    See also Ser.I, The Smithsonian Institution; See also Ser.I, United States Department of the Interior
  - Stewart, Omer C., 1939-1940 (Box 8)
  - Stocking, George W., 1979-1982 (Box 8)
  - Story, Russell M., 1941 (Box 8)
  - Straus, Anne Terry Sawyier, 1968-1974 (Box 8)
  - Strickland, Sharon L., 1971 (Box 8)
  - Stuter, C., n.d. (Box 8)
  - Summer, Elia M., 1958 (Box 8)
  - Tax, Sol (Box 8)
  - Tefft, Stanton K., 1979 (Box 8)
  - Thomas, Frederick J., 1974 (Box 8)
  - Thornton, H.V., 1938 (Box 8)
  - Travel, 1940 (Box 8)
  - Tufts College, 1928 (Box 8)
  - Turnbull, Colin, 1987 (Box 8)
  - Turner, John E. (Box 8)
    See Ser.I, University of Minnesota
  - Twining, William L., 1964-1973, n.d. (Box 8)
  - Unidentified, 1928-1988, n.d. (Box 8)
  - United Press International, 1970 (Box 8)
    See also Ser.I, Goldman, Ira; See also Ser.II, same title
  - United States Arms Control and Disarmament Agency, 1969-1973 (Box 8)
    Mosely, Philip E.; See also Ser.II, same title
  - United States Army Artillery and Missile Center, 1957 (Box 8)
  - United States Department of the Interior, 1934-1936, 1972 (Box 8)
    Mekeel, H. Scudder; Steward, Julian H.
  - United States Department of War, 1945 (Box 8)
  - United States Educational Foundation in the Netherlands, 1969 (Box 8)
  - United States Naval Academy, 1962 (Box 8)
  - United States Navy, 1943 (Box 8)
  - United Pueblos Agency, 1945-1946 (Box 8)
  - United States Senate. Subcommittee on Government Research, 1967 (Box 8)
  - Universität Köln, 1928-1930 (Box 8)
  - Universiteit Van Amsterdam, 1967-1970 (Box 8)
  - The University of Arizona, 1973 (Box 8)
  - University of California, 1940-1984 (Box 8)
    Mandelbaum, David
  - The University of Chicago, 1947, 1989-1992 (Box 8)
    Redfield, Robert
  - The University of Chicago Law Review, 1948 (Box 8)
  - University of Cologne, 1929 (Box 8)
    in French and German
  - University of Colorado, 1951 (Box 8)
  - University of Hawaii, 1963 (Box 8)
  - University of Kansas, 1954-1956 (Box 8)
  - University of Kentucky, 1948 (Box 8)
  - University of Maine (Box 8)
    See Ser.I, Baber, Ray E.
  - University of Manchester, 1958 (Box 8)
  - University of Minnesota, 2 folders (Box 8)
    Burke, Samuel M.; Turner, John E.
    - Folder 1, 1937-1965 (Box 8)
    - Folder 2, 1966-1981 (Box 8)
  - University of Minnesota. University Press Committee, 1969-1972 (Box 8)
  - University of Minnesota Foundation, 1967, 1969 (Box 8)
  - University of Nebraska Press, 1977-1979 (Box 8)
  - University of Oklahoma Press, 1937-1987 (Box 8)
  - University of Oregon, 1953 (Box 8)
  - University of Pittsburgh, 1931 (Box 8)
  - University of Saskatchewan, 1970 (Box 8)
  - University of Tennessee Press, 1977 (Box 9)
  - University of Utah, 1947-1963 (Box 9)
    Durham, G. Homer
  - University of Washington (Box 9)
    See Ser.I, Ray, Verne F.
  - University of Wisconsin, 1925-1969 (Box 9)
    Dittmer, C.G.; Ross, E.A.
  - Utah State University, 1958-1960 (Box 9)
  - Valletta, Joe, 1988 (Box 9)
  - van den Bergh, Govaert, 1974, 1982 (Box 9)
    See also Ser.I, Katholieke Universiteit
  - van den Steenhoven, Geert, 1966-1981, n.d. (Box 9)
  - Van Doren, George, 1982 (Box 9)
  - VanStraaten, J., 1947 (Box 9)
  - Vilakazi, Absolom, 1958 (Box 9)
  - Virginia Law Review, 1945-1946 (Box 9)
  - Visscher, Maurice B., 1968 (Box 9)
  - Von Fürer-Haimendorf, C., 1960 (Box 9)
  - Walck, Al, 1968 (Box 9)
  - Walker Art Center, 1972-1973 (Box 9)
  - Walkup, Lewis E., 1979-1983 (Box 9)
  - Wallace, Ernest, 1980 (Box 9)
    See also Ser.I, Huber, O.A.
  - Wallis, Ruth, 1973, 1975 (Box 9)
  - Wallis, Wilson D., 1941, 1966 (Box 9)
  - War Relocation Authority, 1943-1945, n.d. (Box 9)
  - Warner, W. Lloyd, 1953 (Box 9)
  - Washburn, Sherwood L., Jr., 1979 (Box 9)
  - Weaver, Thomas, 1976-1985 (Box 9)
  - Wenner-Gren Foundation for Anthropological Research, 1955-1983, n.d. (Box 9)
  - Werntz, Jim, 1972 (Box 9)
  - Western Washington College of Education, 1960 (Box 9)
  - White, Douglas R., 1970-1977 (Box 9)
  - White, Leslie A., 1970, 1973 (Box 9)
  - Wiese, L.V., 1953 (Box 9)
  - Wigmore, John H., 1940 (Box 9)
  - Wilkerson, Chris, n.d. (Box 9)
  - Wilkinson, Cragun, Barker and Hawkins, 1957 (Box 9)
  - Willey, Gordon R., 1972 (Box 9)
  - Willey, Malcolm, 1970 (Box 9)
  - Wilson, Alfred, 1935, 1938? (Box 9)
  - Wilson, Marian, 15 May (Box 9)
  - Wilson, Owen Meredith, 1956-1970, n.d. (Box 9)
    See also Ser.I, University of Minnesota
  - Wisdom Hall of Fame, 1970 (Box 9)
  - Wise, Edward Martin, 1963-1964 (Box 9)
  - Wiseman, Zipporah Batshaw, 1992 (Box 9)
  - Wittfogel, Esther S., 1941, 1967 (Box 9)
    Adair, John
  - Wolf, John, 1973-1987, n.d. (Box 9)
    Wolf, Theta
  - Wolf, Theta (Box 9)
    See Ser.I, Wolf, John
  - Wood, W. Raymond, 1983 (Box 9)
  - The World Book Encyclopedia, 1965 (Box 9)
  - Wormsley, Bill, 1980 (Box 9)
  - Xavier, George, 1968 (Box 9)
  - Yong, Zhou, 1992 (Box 9)
  - Yoshida, Shizuo, 1945 (Box 9)
  - Young, Kimbal, 1933 (Box 9)
  - Youngs, Oliver, 1942 (Box 9)
  - Zamora, Mario D., 1987-1990 (Box 9)
  - Zaputovich, Maria, 1973 (Box 9)
  - Zeigler, Bob, 1958, 1962 (Box 9)
  - Ziebarth, E.W., 1980, 1984-1988, n.d. (Box 9)
  - Zigmond, Maurice L., 1941 (Box 9)
  - Zimmerman, Michael, 1972 (Box 9)
  - Zion, James W., 1984 (Box 9)
- Series II. Subject files, 1927-1993; 4 boxes; 2.0 linear feet
  Reports, clippings, programs, transcripts, awards, and reviews and publishers' promotional materials for Hoebel's books. The folders are arranged alphabetically by topic, and items within the files are arranged chronologically. Seven of the files contain case reports from the archives of the United Pueblos Agency, which Hoebel and Llewellyn used to supplement their research on the law-ways of the Keresan Pueblo Indians. This series also includes materials documenting Hoebel's career at the universities of Utah and Minnesota, as well as his involvement in the War Relocation Authority, the World Law Project, and the Arms Control and Disarmament Agency. A file with biographical information is included in this series.
  - Airlangga University, 1973 (Box 10)
  - American Anthropological Association, 1955-1984, n.d. (Box 10)
  - American Faculty Council for the Gradualist Way to Peace, n.d. (Box 10)
  - The American Judicature Society, 1970-1971 (Box 10)
  - American Philosophical Society, 1963 (Box 10)
  - Anthropology: The Study of Man, 1966-1968, n.d. (Box 10)
  - Artifacts from New Guinea, 1969 (Box 10)
  - The Association for Anthropological Diplomacy, 1982 (Box 10)
  - Bethel Couvade, 1977 (Box 11)
  - Bibliography, 4 folders (Box 11)
    See also Ser.IV, De Micheli Consonni, Cristina, "Bibliographie des Oeuvres de E.A. Hoebel"
    - Folder 1, 1935-1947 (Box 11)
    - Folder 2, 1948-1963 (Box 11)
    - Folder 3, 1964-1984 (Box 11)
    - Folder 4, [197-] (Box 11)
  - Biographical Materials, 1929-1993, n.d. (Box 11)
    See also Ser.III, "Autobiographical Statement"
  - Center for Cultural and Technical Interchange between East and West, 1966 (Box 11)
  - The Cheyenne Way: Conflict and Case Law in Primitive Jurisprudence, 1939-1942, n.d. (Box 11)
  - Clippings, 1953-1981 (Box 11)
  - The Comanches: Lords of the South Plains--Reviews, 1952-1953, 1982, 1988 (Box 11)
  - A Conference on the Status of Research and Teaching in Anthropology of the Southwest, 7 Apr. 1951 (Box 11)
  - Conference Transcript, n.d. (Box 11)
  - Cultural and Social Anthropology (Box 11)
  - Dispute Processing: Legal and Anthropological Perspectives, [198-] (Box 11)
  - Grand Canyon Expedition, 1968-1971, 1982 (Box 11)
  - Handbook of North American Indians, 1971 (Box 11)
    See also Ser.I, same title
  - "The Ik", 1976 (Box 11)
  - Katholieke Universiteit, 1968-1973 (Box 11)
  - Law and Society Association, 1989 (Box 11)
  - The Law of Primitive Man, 1955, n.d. (Box 11)
  - Lehigh University, 1980 (Box 11)
  - Man in the Primitive World, 1949-1959, n.d. (Box 11)
  - Map of Western American Indians (Box 11)
    See Oversized